<page id="templates">
    <ident>$Id: index.xml 2095 2011-12-14 17:40:52Z massimo.manghi $</ident>
    <author>$Author: massimo.manghi $</author>
    <date>$Date: 2011-12-14 18:40:52 +0100 (Wed, 14 Dec 2011) $</date>
    <title>Modello di Pagina</title>
    <headline>Modello di Pagina</headline>
    <menu position="left">root,level1</menu>
    <content>
    	<title>Pagina Modello del Sito</title>
    	<headline>Modello per una pagina di contenuti</headline>
        <pagetext>
            <!-- all'interno di pagetext va un testo xhtml valido  -->
				<p style="background: lightblue; border: 2px solid black; padding: 2em">
					Rivetweb has its own webspace at <externref href="http://www.rivetweb.org">http://www.rivetweb.org/</externref>
				</p>
            
            <p>Example of init.tcl script</p>
            <programlisting>
namespace eval ::rivetweb {
    set site_base	    [pwd]
    set rivet_scripts	[file join [file dirname [info script]] .. tcl]
}

apache_log_error err "Rivetweb: $::rivetweb::site_base"
source [file join $::rivetweb::rivet_scripts rivet_init.tcl]
source [file join $::rivetweb::site_base rivet_defs.tcl]
                
            </programlisting>
            <div>
            <p style="background: lightblue; border: 2px solid black; padding: 2em">

                ... For history of times representeth the magnitude of actions, 
                and the public faces and deportments of persons, and passeth over 
                in silence the smaller passages and motions of men and matters. 
                But such being the workmanship of God, as He doth hang the greatest weight 
                upon the smallest wires, maxima e minimis, suspendens, it comes therefore 
                to pass, that such histories do rather set forth the pomp of business 
                than the true and inward resorts thereof... 
                <span style="text-align: right; margin: 1em;display: block; padding: 0.5em; background: white;">Francis Bacon</span>
            </p>
            <photolink src="242px-Borromean_Rings_Illusion.png" fullres="1032px-Borromean_Rings_Illusion.png" download="1" />
            <p>
                Elementary particles are particles for which there is no known way of 
                dividing them into smaller units. Theoretical and experimental studies 
                have shown that the spin possessed by such particles cannot be explained 
                by postulating that they are made up of even smaller particles rotating 
                about a common center of mass (see classical electron radius); as far as 
                <image src="spin.png" class="floatleft"/>
                can be determined, these elementary particles are true point particles. The 
                spin of an elementary particle is a truly intrinsic physical property, 
                akin to the particle's electric charge and rest 
                <sitereference href="mass">mass</sitereference>.<br />
                Let the spin quantum number s be n/2, where n can be any non-negative integer.
                Hence the allowed values of s are 0, 1/2, 1, 3/2, 2, etc. The value of s for an 
                elementary particle depends only on the type of particle, and cannot be altered in 
                any known way (in contrast to the spin direction described below). The spin angular
                momentum S of any physical system is quantized. The allowed values of S are:
            </p>
            </div>
        </pagetext>
    </content>
</page>
