<page id="index">
    <ident>$Ident: Thu Nov 08, 2012 at 11:11 AM +0100
    </ident>
    <author>$Author: massimo.manghi $</author>
    <date>$Date: 2011-12-14 18:40:52 +0100 (Wed, 14 Dec 2011) $</date>
    <title>Modello di Pagina</title>
    <headline>Modello di Pagina</headline>
    <menu position="left">main</menu>
    <content>
        <title>Rivetweb: easy HTML generation with Tcl</title>
        <headline>Rivetweb: easy HTML generation with Tcl</headline>
        <pagetext>
        <p>
            Rivetweb is a minimum requirements Tcl engine for creating template
            based websites. The only required software packages you need are 
            the <externref href="http://httpd.apache.org/">Apache HTTP Webserver</externref>, 
            <externref href="http://tcl.apache.org/rivet/">Apache Rivet</externref> and (in 
            <image src="141px-Borromean.png" align="left" />
            the current implementation) also 
            <externref href="http://tdom.github.com">tdom</externref> is used to 
            manipulate data and XHTML ouput.
        </p>
        <p>
            Rivetweb internal machinery and organizazion is entirely developed in 
            Tcl. Rivetweb was written with an emphasis on indipendence from the 
            actual implementation of its components 
            and aims at evolving to a simple yet
            fully customizable, extensible framework for simple websites. 
        </p>
        <h3>What <b>Rivetweb</b> can do for you</h3>
        <p>
            Rivetweb was born as a simple application to create 
            websites whose content is static and, if needed, available 
            in different languages. It proved to be a useful ground 
            where workgroups developing static documentation to be published 
            on the web could work together focusing their efforts on page writing 
            and on the site structure (see 
            <sitereference href="examples">Examples</sitereference>) organization.
            Unlike other powerful open source publishing tools (namely 
            <externref href="http://www.docbook.org/">Docbook</externref>)
            Rivetweb doesn't come with a rich set of semantic tags ready to use 
            (except for a few inherently needed tags like <b>sitereference</b>), 
            but has a simple mechanism that lets you add Tcl written
            hooks to transform and/or expand specific element of a page into 
            full XHTML code. Rivetweb is meant to be a blank canvas where Tcl'ers can
            add markup language transformations or combine datasource
            to create web sites.
        </p>
        <h3><b>Rivetweb</b> as an HTML generator</h3>
        <p>
            When links in a Rivetweb site are consistently written with the <b>sitereference</b>
            tag the whole website can be generated as if every page was stored in a good
            old fashioned .html page. By setting up Apache mod_rewrite with a few configuration 
            lines the whole website can be cloned into static <em>.html</em> pages and then 
            deployed with <b>any</b> webserver with no backend needed at all. 
            When used for this purpose Rivetweb is a good tool to generate documentation 
            that is not going to change every second (even though recreating it can be done 
            easily or even automated with scripts)
        </p>
        <p>
            Rivetweb supports multiple templates at once. You can take several
            templates, adapt them to show your pages and run the website with
            as many templates as you like. Your website changes appearance
            by simply starting the browsing with a an extra urlencoded parameter
            <em>template=&lt;template_name&gt;</em>
        </p>
      </pagetext>
    </content>
    <content language="it">
        <title>Rivetweb: semplice generatore di HTML basato su Tcl</title>
        <pagetext>
            <p>Il sito di Rivetweb e' in costruzione</p>
            <programlisting src="README" /> 
        </pagetext>
    </content>
</page>
