<page id="spin">
    <ident>$Id: spin.xml 1064 2011-05-03 16:04:31Z massimo.manghi $</ident>
    <author>$Author: massimo.manghi $</author>
    <date>$Date: 2011-05-03 18:04:31 +0200 (Tue, 03 May 2011) $</date>
    <title>Spin of a Particle</title>
    <headline>Spin of a Particle</headline>
    <menu position="left">level2</menu>
    <content>
    	<title>Spin of a particle</title>
    	<headline>Spin of a Particle</headline>
	    <pagetext>
	        <div>
                <p>

                    In quantum mechanics and particle physics, spin is a fundamental characteristic 
                    property of elementary particles, composite particles (hadrons), and atomic nuclei.
		</p>
		<p>
                    All elementary particles of a given kind have the same spin quantum number, an important 
                    part of a particle's quantum state. When combined with the spin-statistics theorem, the spin 
                    of electrons results in the Pauli exclusion principle, which in turn underlies the periodic 
                    table of chemical elements. The spin direction (also called spin for short) of a particle is 
                    an important intrinsic degree of freedom.
		</p>
		<p>
                    Wolfgang Pauli was the first to propose the concept of spin, but he did not name it. 
                    In 1925, Ralph Kronig, George Uhlenbeck, and Samuel Goudsmit suggested a physical interpretation 
                    of particles spinning around their own axis. The mathematical theory was worked out in depth by 
                    Pauli in 1927. When Paul Dirac derived his relativistic quantum mechanics in 1928, 
                    electron spin was an essential part of it.
		</p>
		<p>
                    Spin is a type of angular momentum, where angular momentum is defined in the modern way 
                    (as the "generator of rotations", see Noether's theorem).[1][2] This modern definition of angular 
                    momentum is not the same as the historical classical mechanics definition, L = r × p. (The historical 
                    definition, which does not include spin, is more specifically called "orbital angular momentum".)

                    Since spin is a type of angular momentum, it has the same dimensions: J·s in SI units. In practice, 
                    however, SI units are almost never used to describe spin: Instead, it is written as a multiple of the 
                    reduced Planck constant ħ. In natural units, the ħ is omitted, so the units of spin are implied. 
                    However, by definition the "spin quantum number" is always dimensionless.
                </p>
	        </div>
	    </pagetext>
    </content>
</page>
